Guide to the Cornell University Board of Trustees records, 1865-2001.
Cornell University Board of Trustees records
- Series I. Board of Trustees
  - Subseries Ia. Working Files
    - Working files, 1951-07 - 1951-10 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 1952-01 - 1952-05 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    - Working files, 1952-05 - 1952-06 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Includes Board on Traffic Control minutes, copy of The Cornell Graduate in Industry study
    - Working files, 1952-09 - 1952-10 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1953-01 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Includes discussion of new men's dormitories
    - Working files, 1953-02 - 1953-10 (Box 19, Folder 9-11)
    - Working files, 1954-02 - 1954-03 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Working files, 1954-04 - 1954-06 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Includes Deane Mallott's statement on deferred rushing
    - Working files, 1954-09 - 1954-11 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      Includes "From Now to 1960--A Preview", annual report of the president,
    - Working files, 1955-01 - 1955-02 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Includes report on increase in Women students
    - Working files, 1955-05 - 1955-10 (Box 20, Folder 2-4)
    - Working files, 1956-01 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Includes statement to the Trustees by Jacob Gould Schurman
    - Working files, 1956-03 - 1956-04 (Box 20, Folder 6-7)
      Includes plans for research library (including floor plans)
    - Working files, 1956-05 - 1956-10 (Box 20, Folder 8-9)
    - Working files, 1957-01 - 1957-04 (Box 20, Folder 10-11)
    - Working files, 1957-05 - 1957-11 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Working files, 1958-01 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Includes letter against destruction of Boardman Hall
      Access restrictions apply.
    - Working files, 1958-02 - 1958-04 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Working files, 1958-05 - 1958-06 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Includes folder of election material
    - Working files, 1958-09 - 1958-11 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1959-01 - 1959-04 (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
    - Working files, 1959-03 - 1959-06 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      Includes Student Government Constitution
    - Working files, 1959-09 - 1959-11 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Working files, 1960-01 - 1960-04 (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
    - Working files, 1960-05 - 1960-07 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Includes copy of Student Code
    - Working files, 1960-08 - 1960-10 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 4-6)
    - Working files, 1962-01 - 1962-04 (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - Working files, 1962-05 - 1962-06 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Includes photograph of Industrial and Labor Relations faculty
    - Working files, 1962-10 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Special meeting Working files, 1963-01 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Regarding election of President Perkins
    - Working files, 1963-01 - 1963-07 (Box 23, Folder 3-5)
    - Working files, 1963-09 - 1963-10 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Includes Unit Share System Material
    - Working files, 1964-01 - 1964-04 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1964-01 - 1964-04 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1964-01 - 1964-04 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Working files, 1964-05 - 1964-06 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      Includes proposal to Air Force Office of Scientific Research for Continuation of Contract AF49(638)-1156
    - Working files, 1964-09 - 1964-10 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1964-12 - 1965-04 (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
    - Working files, 1965-04 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Includes review of Synchrotron, discontent among students regarding education
    - Working files, 1965-05 - 1965-10 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
    - Working files, 1965-12 - 1966-04 (Box 24, Folder 7-9)
    - Working files, 1966-05 - 1966-10 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    - Working files, 1967-01 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 1967-02 - 1967-06 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
      Includes announcements of Cornell Heights Residential Club fire, residential reports
    - Working files, 1967-07 - 1967-10 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1967-12 - 1968-04 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
    - Working files, 1968-05-1968-12 (Box 79, Folder 31-32)
    - Working files, 1969-01 (Box 79, Folder 33)
      Includes report of the Presidential Committee on Military Training
    - Working files, 1969-03-1969-04 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Includes personnel change of status
    - Working files, 1969-05 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      Includes Willard Straight Takeover resolutions and press releases, nullification of judicial procedures taken against students, statements by Perkins and Corson, statements on collection of firearms, State Act 7082, motion on racism task forces,
    - Working files, 1969-06 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      Includes press releases on the president and personnel change of status
    - Working files, 1969-09 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Working files, 1969-10 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      Includes background reading for COSEP and Afro-American studies, personnel change in status
    - Working files, 1970-01-1970-03 (Box 80, Folder 6-7)
    - Tenure appointments, 1970-04 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1970-04 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Working files, 1970-05-1970-06 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Board Personnel Actions, 1970-06 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1970-10 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 1971-01 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Working files, 1971-04 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Board Personnel Actions, 1971-04 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1971-05-1971-06 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1971-07 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1971-10 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1972-01-1972-10 (Box 82, Folder 2-5)
    - Working files, 1973-01-1973-04 (Box 82, Folder 6-8)
    - Working files, 1973-10 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1974-01-1974-10 (Box 83, Folder 2-5)
    - Trustee Orientation, Undated (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1975-01-1975-03 (Box 83, Folder 7-8)
    - Working files, 1975-06 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1975-10 (Box 84, Folder 2)
      Includes report of the Trustee Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Minorities,
    - Working files, 1976-01 (Box 84, Folder 3)
      Includes packet of information on the Nguyen Cao Ky incident at Bailey Hall,
    - Working files, 1976-03-1976-10 (Box 84, Folder 4-5)
    - Working files, 1977-01 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1977-02-1977-10 (Box 85, Folder 1-4)
    - Working files, 1978-01-1978-05 (Box 85, Folder 5-7)
    - Working files, 1978-05 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1978-10 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Working files, 1979-01-1979-10 (Box 86, Folder 1-4)
    - Trustee Orientation, 1979-12 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Working files, 1980-01-1980-05 (Box 86, Folder 6-8)
    - Trustee Orientation, 1980-09 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Working files, 1980-10 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1981-01 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1981-03-1981-05 (Box 87, Folder 3-4)
      Includes President Rhodes' statement on the occupation of Day Hall
    - Cornell Trustees/SUNY Trustees, 1981-04 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Orientation, 1981-09 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1981-10 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Orientation, 1982-01 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1982-01 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      Includes information on Zahorik et al v. Cornell
    - Working files, 1982-03 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1982-05 (Box 88, Folder 3)
      Includes Report of the Board Study Committee
    - Working files, 1982-05 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Orientation of New Trustees, 1982-09 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Working files, 1982-10 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1982-12 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1983-01 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1983-04-1983-05 (Box 89, Folder 1-2)
    - Working files, 1983-05 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Orientation, 1983-10 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Working files, 1983-10 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Working files, 1984-01 (Box 89, Folder 6)
      Includes review of minority education at Cornell
    - Working files, 1984-03 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1984-05 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Orientation, 1984-09 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1984-10 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1985-01-1985-10 (Box 90, Folder 3-6)
    - Orientation, 1985-10 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1986-01 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      Includes reports and information on South African Divestment
    - Working files, 1986-03-1986-05 (Box 90, Folder 9-10)
    - Orientation, 1986 (Box 92, Folder 24)
    - Orientation, 1986-06 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1986-10 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1987-01-1987-03 (Box 93, Folder 3-4)
    - Working files, 1987-05-1987-10 (Box 93, Folder 5-6)
    - Orientation, 1987-10 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Working files, 1988-01-1988-03 (Box 93, Folder 8-9)
    - Working files, 1988-05 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Orientation, 1988-07 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 1988-10 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 1989-01-1989-12 (Box 94, Folder 4-7)
    - Working files, 1994-01 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1994-05-1994-06 (Box 95, Folder 1-2)
    - Orientation, 1994-06 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 1994-10-1994-12 (Box 95, Folder 4-5)
    - Working files, 1995-03-1995-05 (Box 95, Folder 6-7)
    - Orientation, 1995-09 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Working files, 1995-10 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Working files, 1996-01-1996-06 (Box 95, Folder 10-11)
    - Orientation, 1996-06 (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Working files, 1996-10 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Working files, 1997-01-1997-05 (Box 96, Folder 2-4)
    - Orientation, 1997-06 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Working files, 1997-10 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Working files, 1998 (Box 96, Folder 7-10)
    - Working files, 1999-01-1999-05 (Box 96, Folder 11-13)
    - Orientation, 1999-06 (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - Working files, 1999-10 (Box 96, Folder 15)
    - Working files, 2000-01-2000-03 (Box 96, Folder 16-17)
    - Working files, 2000-05 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Orientation, 2000-06 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Working files, 2000-10 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Working files, 2001-01-2001-06 (Box 97, Folder 4-6)
    - Appointment Letters, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 1-4)
    - Appointment Letters, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 5-8)
    - Appointment Letters, 1987 (Box 91, Folder 9-13)
    - Appointment Letters, 1988-01-1988-03 (Box 91, Folder 14-15)
    - Appointment Letters, 1988-05-1988-10 (Box 92, Folder 1-3)
    - Appointment Letters, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 4-10)
    - Appointment Letters, 1990 (Box 92, Folder 11-17)
    - Appointment Letters, 1991-01-1991-05 (Box 92, Folder 18-23)
  - Subseries Ib. Minutes
    - Trustee Minutes, 1864-1866-11 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Trustee Minutes, bound, 1865-1885 (Box 101)
      Includes a signed cabinet card of Ezra Cornell glued on the inside cover
    - Trustee Minutes, 1867-02-1867-11 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Trustee Minutes, bound abstracts, 1868-1893 (Box 101)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1868-02-1868-10 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1869-02-1869-06 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1870-02-1970-06 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1871-06 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1872-02 (Box 98, Folder 6)
      Includes resolution on the formation of a Women's College
    - Trustee Minutes, 1872-06 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1873-06 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1874-07-1874-11 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1875-06 (Box 98, Folder 9)
      Includes comments and condolences following the death of Ezra Cornell
    - Trustee Minutes, 1876-06 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1877-06 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1878-06 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1879-06-1880-06 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1881 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1882-06 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1883-10 (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1884-06-1884-10 (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1885-06-1885-10 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1886-06-1886-10 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1887-01-1887-10 (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1888-06-1889-06 (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1890-06-1891-10 (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1892-02-1892-11 (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1893-10 (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1894-06-1894-11 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1895-06-1895-11 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1896-10 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1898-04-1898-06 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1904 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1905-10 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1906 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1907 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1908-1909 (Box 98, Folder 22)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1910 (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1911 (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1912 (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1913 (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1914 (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1915 (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1916 (Box 98, Folder 29)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1917 (Box 98, Folder 30)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1920 (Box 98, Folder 31)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1921-1922 (Box 98, Folder 32)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1923 (Box 98, Folder 33)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1924-1925 (Box 98, Folder 34)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1926-1927 (Box 98, Folder 35)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1928-1929 (Box 98, Folder 36)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1930-1931 (Box 98, Folder 37)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1932 (Box 98, Folder 38)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1933 (Box 98, Folder 39)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1934-1940 (Box 99, Folder 1-7)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1941-1946 (Box 99, Folder 8-11)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1953-1965 (Box 99, Folder 12-15)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1966-1978 (Box 99, Folder 16-20)
    - Trustee Minutes, 1979-2001 (Box 99, Folder 21-26)
- Series II. Executive Committee
  - Subseries Ia. Working Files
    Files include correspondence, appropriations, conspectus, budget reports, appointments, resignations, applications, land sales/purchases, and tenure requests
    - Working file, 1868-10 - 1870-12 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Includes report of the librarian and list of donors, buildings report, accounts and expenses, trustee requests to Ezra Cornell to sell land scrip
    - Working file, 1871-01 - 1872-02 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence on sale of Jared Sparks library
    - Working file, 1872-03 - 1876 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence on sale of Jared Sparks library, private printing of "Some statements and Estimates of Immediate Wants Laid before the Trustees by the Scientific Professors and the Librarian, 1873"
    - Working file, 1876-08 - 1877-11 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence regarding hours and uses of the library, anonymous letter regarding indecent bathing in the creek
    - Working file, 1878-01 - 1879-06 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Includes report of committee on the regulations at Sage College
    - Working file, 1879-07 - 1879-12 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Working file, 1880-01 - 1880-06 (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
    - Working file, 1880-07 - 1880-09 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Includes plan of organization of an Experiment Station
    - Working file, 1880-10 - 1880-12 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Includes report on water safety, map of proposed lots, report of the committee on Veterinary Department
    - Working file, 1881-01 - 1881-03 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Includes proposal for Physics building
    - Working file, 1881-04 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      Includes report on conditions of Cascadilla Place, Report of the survey of Cornell Campus to George Schuyler by EA Fuertes (includes survey map), petition to decline resignation of William Russell
    - Working file, 1881-05 - 1881-06 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Includes petition to decline resignation of William Russell, petition from women to decline resignation of William Russell, EA Fuertes letter in regard to NY Times accusation, indenture between Cornell and Henry Sage for gymnasium lot, letter from AD White about purchase of casts, plan for Department of History and Political Science
    - Working file, 1881-07 - 1881-10 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      Includes correspondence and sketch of Michigan University Library and White's sketch of proposed Cornell University Library
    - Working file, 1881-10 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      Includes drawing of campus with proposed walkways
    - Working file, 1881-11 - 1881-12 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      Includes handwritten chart of weather predictions for 1880-1882 by E. Fuertes from the signal station, sketch for Foundry and Blacksmith Hall, ratio of students to teachers in leading American colleges
    - Working file, 1882-01 - 1882-04 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      Includes petition from faculty to provide baseball fields
    - Working file, 1882-04 - 1882-05 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Working file, 1882-05 - 1882-06 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      Includes sketch of observatory by E.A. Fuertes
    - Working file, 1882-06 - 1882-11 (Box 26, Folder 20-21)
    - Working file, 1882-11 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      Includes resolution establishing the Library Council, testimony of students involved in the destruction of the bridge.
    - Working file, 1882-12 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      Includes first annual report of the Archaeological Institute of America, E.A. Fuertes inventory of private property
    - Working file, 1883-01 - 1883-03 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      Includes resolution to establish a museum council
    - Working file, 1883-03 - 1883-04 (Box 26, Folder 25)
      Includes letter from Charles Babcock about plans for a library,
    - Working file, 1883-05 - 1883-06 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      Includes resolutions regarding the Jennie Fiske Hospital, copy of a pamphlet on Sage College for Women, copies of clippings
    - Working file, 1883-06 - 1883-07 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      Includes petition from students against dismissal of Professor McKoon, Psi Upsilon request for property, naming of White and Morrill Halls
    - Working file, 1883-08 - 1883-09 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      Includes Burt Greene Wilder's application as curator of Vertebrate Zoology, proposal of lectures on forestry
    - Working file, 1883-10 - 1883-11 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Working file, 1883-12 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      Includes letter from George W. Harris requesting to be made head of the library, report from AD White on the memorial windows in Sage Chapel, list of purchased plaster casts of Lincoln Cathedral
    - Working file, 1883 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      Includes observatory estimates, letter about aid for students supporting themselves, resolution postponing the building of the observatory to a later date
    - Working file, 1884-01 - 1884-02 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      Includes proposal for a school of comparative palaeontology, petition from Bicycle Club asking permission to ride in the gymnasium, resolutions establishing the Gymnasium Council,
    - Working file, 1884-03 - 1884-04 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Working file, 1884-05 - 1884-06 (Box 26, Folder 34)
      Includes petition from the Board of Education of Ithaca
    - Working file on advertising Cornell, 1884-05 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Working file, 1884-06 - 1884-08 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Working file, 1884-09 (Box 26, Folder 37)
      Includes resolutions on fellowships and scholarships,
    - Working file, 1884-10 - 1884-12 (Box 26, Folder 38)
      Includes resolution and statutes on the establishment of a College of Pharmacy with letters from professors and University of Michigan
    - Working file, 1884 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Working file, 1885-01 - 1885-04 (Box 26, Folder 40)
      Includes petition from students to put a hand rail on the Willow Pond bridge, letter requesting renovations to the ladies room in Morrill, petition to reinstate Chi Psi
    - Working file, 1885-05 - 1885-06 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Working file, 1885-07 (Box 26, Folder 42)
      Includes letter from Charles Kendall Adams accepting the presidency
    - Working file, 1885-08 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Working file, 1885-09 - 1885-12 (Box 26, Folder 44)
      Includes report of Committee on Salaries and Reorganization of Departments, Gluck's suggestions on increase of professor salaries and university reorganization,
    - Working file, 1886-01 - 1886-03 (Box 26, Folder 45)
      Includes request for lot from Seabury Guild
    - Working file, 1886-04 (Box 26, Folder 46)
      Includes hand drawn map of campus with professors' homes
    - Working file, 1886-05 - 1886-06 (Box 26, Folder 47)
      Includes Burt Green Wilder's requests for a manatee and other taxidermy animals
    - Working file, 1886-06 - 1886-10 (Box 26, Folder 48)
      Includes petition for provisions for Roehrig's retirement,
    - Working file, 1886-10 (Box 26, Folder 49)
      Includes petition from the Tompkins County Agricultural Society for a building to be built for exhibitions, arrival of Edison's donation of the Dynamo-electric machine and installation, report on the proper organization of the Law Department
    - Working file, 1886-11 - 1886-12 (Box 26, Folder 50)
      Includes request to use the armory for military hops,
    - Working file, 1887-01 - 1887-04 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Includes letter on cadet rifles, report of the committee on Applied Science, list of seniors in civil engineering,
    - Working file, 1887-05 - 1887-09 (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
    - Working file, 1887-10 - 1887-12 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Includes letter from Burt Green Wilder regarding preservation of elephant brain
    - Working file, 1887 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Working file, 1888-01 - 1888-07 (Box 27, Folder 6-8)
    - Working file, 1888-08 - 1888-10 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Includes proposed organization of the Department of Water Supply, Heat and Power, catalogue of books in library of W. Newcomb, letter from EA Fuertes on the poor condition of drinking water
    - Working file, 1888-11 - 1888-12 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Includes report of the physique of Cornell students
    - Working file, 1889-01 - 1889-02 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Includes report on disinfection of Sage following smallpox scare,
    - Working file, 1889-02 - 1889-03 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Working file, 1889-04 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Includes library report
    - Working file, 1889-04 - 1889-06 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Includes map of proposed line of street Rail Road, report on the needs and conditions of Sibley College,
    - Working file, 1889-06 - 1889-07 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Working file, 1889-08 - 1889-10 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      Includes letter requesting a room for childcare from wives of faculty,
    - Working file, 1889-10 - 1889-12 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      Includes sketched plan of Fall Creek dam and reservoir
    - Working file, 1890-01 - 1890-03 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      Includes report on Sibley College organization
    - Working file, 1890-03 - 1890-04 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      Includes report of the Committee of Senate on the chair of Rhetoric and English Philology
    - Working file, 1890-05 - 1890-06 (Box 27, Folder 20)
      Includes report on Sage College, letter from Health Board of the university of the imminent danger of measles
    - Working file, 1890-06 (Box 27, Folder 21)
      Includes report of operations and power, dynamo plan from Sibley College
    - Working file, 1890-07 - 1890-09 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      Includes copy of courses of instruction in engineering
    - Working file, 1890-10 - 1890-11 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      Includes appointment of G.L. Burr as librarian of White Library with resolutions, statute establishing University Senate,
    - Working file, 1890-12 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Working file, 1891-01 - 1891-02 (Box 27, Folder 25)